<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-23T14:26:17-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Nicki Peternel’s Personal Website</title><subtitle>Personal Website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Photo Framer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/01/photo-framer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photo Framer" /><published>2020-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/01/photo-framer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/10/01/photo-framer.html">&lt;p&gt;The Photo Framer is a Slack app that generates custom profile picture frames in a company’s Slack workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mapbox has a custom Slack command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@mapbox&lt;/code&gt; with a wide variety of commands, from meme generations to &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mapbox.com/building-on-call-mapboxs-managed-incident-response-tool-59fadd87317a&quot;&gt;incident response&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020, when Hacktober, our annual Hacktober security-awareness month, was coming up, we realized we’d no longer be able to continue our annual tradition of awarding physical participation stickers because the entire company was remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A co-worker and I set out to solve this problem using a unique asset that every person at the company has: their Slack profile picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added a new custom Slack command called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@mapbox photo-frame&lt;/code&gt;, where a user can specify which photo frame they want to apply to their Slack profile picture. For example, if I sent the Slack message &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@mapbox photo-frame hacktober2020&lt;/code&gt;, I’d receive a direct message from our Photo Framer Slack app that automatically frames my current Slack profile picture with a fun Hacktober frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/photo-framer/hacktober.png&quot; alt=&quot;hacktober&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we soon realized this didn’t need to be limited to Hacktober participation! Right as October ended, another major event was approaching: Election Day. “I Voted” stickers are typically distributed at polling places after a ballot is cast, but again, due to the limited, in-person interactions this year, most folks were probably not voting by mail or able to sport their sticker. So we added another photo frame!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/photo-framer/i-voted.png&quot; alt=&quot;i-voted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal here is that as we continue to shelter-in-place, we can continue to drive virtual engagement through this Slack app. Anyone in the company can contribute their own frame - all it takes is a Pull Request with a PNG file and a 3-line code change!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Photo Framer is a Slack app that generates custom profile picture frames in a company’s Slack workspace.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scattergories</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/24/scattergories.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scattergories" /><published>2020-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/24/scattergories</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/24/scattergories.html">&lt;p&gt;Online, multiplayer version of the popular board game &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scattergories&quot;&gt;Scattergories&lt;/a&gt; hosted on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scattergories was a solo project I undertook early on during shelter-in-place. My partner and I were getting bored of watching Netflix and started playing board games in our free time. We re-discovered Scattergories, a game we both played when we were younger, but soon realized we were spending a lot of time writing lists from 1-10 and wasting a lot of paper. Simultaneously, I had been itching to learn React to understand what the hype was all about. Thus, Scattergories was born. Scattergories is a basic website powered by React on the frontend and Express/Node.js on the backend. The site is hosted on AWS using EC2. I also experimented with AWS CodeDeploy for the first time to build the source code for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the website only supports one game at a time and has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/npeternel/scattergories&quot;&gt;number of additional features&lt;/a&gt; I’d like to implement some day, for now it accomplished my two major desires: a deep dive into React and an eco-friendly, time-saving way to play Scattergories!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;scattergories.nickip.me&quot;&gt;scattergories.nickip.me&lt;/a&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Online, multiplayer version of the popular board game Scattergories hosted on AWS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Started at Mapbox</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/09/mapbox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Started at Mapbox" /><published>2019-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/09/mapbox</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/09/mapbox.html">&lt;p&gt;Started a new job at Mapbox in San Francisco on the Platform team. My focus is on operational and security strategies to support and secure Mapbox’s AWS infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Started a new job at Mapbox in San Francisco on the Platform team. My focus is on operational and security strategies to support and secure Mapbox’s AWS infrastructure</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">viocli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/03/viocli.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="viocli" /><published>2019-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/03/viocli</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/03/viocli.html">&lt;p&gt;Command line interface with over 30 new features for VMware Integrated OpenStack (VIO) 6.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-Integrated-OpenStack/6.0/rn/VMware-Integrated-OpenStack-60-Release-Notes.html&quot;&gt;VIO 6.0 release notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Command line interface with over 30 new features for VMware Integrated OpenStack (VIO) 6.0</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moved to San Francisco</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/01/moved.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moved to San Francisco" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/01/moved</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/01/moved.html">&lt;p&gt;Became a frequent SFMTA consumer&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Became a frequent SFMTA consumer</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Started Full-Time at VMware</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/16/vmwarestart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Started Full-Time at VMware" /><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/16/vmwarestart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/07/16/vmwarestart.html">&lt;p&gt;Began my first full-time Software Engineering role at VMware, diving into the world of containers, microservices, and Kubernetes&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Began my first full-time Software Engineering role at VMware, diving into the world of containers, microservices, and Kubernetes</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graduated from UC Berkeley</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/27/graduation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graduated from UC Berkeley" /><published>2018-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/27/graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/27/graduation.html">&lt;p&gt;Completed my Bachelor’s Degree in Electrical Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Science&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Completed my Bachelor’s Degree in Electrical Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Science</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Attendy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/25/attendy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attendy" /><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/25/attendy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/25/attendy.html">&lt;p&gt;Django web application created for professors to track attendance and participation of their students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voted best project for design, functionality, and implementation amongst 11 teams&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Django web application created for professors to track attendance and participation of their students</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interned at VMware</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/16/internship.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interned at VMware" /><published>2017-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/16/internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/16/internship.html">&lt;p&gt;Participated in a Software Engineering internship at VMware&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Participated in a Software Engineering internship at VMware</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Overview of New Zealand’s North Island</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/31/sample.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Overview of New Zealand's North Island" /><published>2017-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/31/sample</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/31/sample.html">&lt;p&gt;During my semester abroad at Auckland University, I had a 2 week mid-semester break, which I used to travel around the North Island of New Zealand using the Kiwi Experience bus route. Essentially, this is a pre-determined tour with various stops throughout all of New Zealand. Through this company, you can book excursions and hostels, making it very convenient for a solo backpacker like me to travel around without renting a car, worrying about being alone, etc. This post won’t go too much into the details of my time with Kiwi Experience but will instead focus on what I saw on the North Island throughout my entire semester, including other weekend trips. To make things organized, I’ll start with my weekend trips (since they were all north of the Kiwi Experience trip) and then work my way down south. At the end I have included a &lt;a href=&quot;#tips&quot;&gt;tips&lt;/a&gt; section with a summary of advice I would give to anyone about to travel through the North Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cape-reinga&quot;&gt;Cape Reinga&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a weekend trip, I drove with two friends all the way up to the most northern tip of New Zealand, Cape Reinga. We stayed in an Airbnb on the Karikari Peninsula so we could easily drive around the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Te Paki Sand Dunes&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Te Paki Sand Dunes --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got to slide down giant sand dunes on boogey boards and see the sunset at the Cape Reinga lighthouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/reinga.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cape Reinga at sunset&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Cape Reinga at sunset --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our drive back down to Auckland, we made a large, long detour to see New Zealand’s oldest Kauri tree.
Overall, I am glad I got to check these activities off my New Zealand bucket list, but the drive was very much out of the way. If I were doing a trip around the North Island (which would probably start in Auckland), I’m not sure I would drive all the way up just for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bay-of-islands&quot;&gt;Bay of Islands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/sailboat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our sailboat stopped at an island to allow us to swim and snorkel&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Our sailboat stopped at an island to allow us to swim and snorkel --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the Bay of Islands twice and learned that the must-do activity there is sailing. The first time, I simply hiked and walked around but that won’t get you out onto the water to see what this area is all about. Though this is north of Auckland and “out of the way” of a journey headed south, if you are willing to spend the money to go out sailing, it could be worth it. Both times, I stayed in Paihia, a cute little town on the water which has a cute little outdoor market of goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/rainbow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow Falls&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Rainbow Falls --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is also known for its waterfalls. If you are feeling a bit adventurous, I would highly recommend going to the Rainbow Falls in Kerikeri. You can swim inside and, if you’re feeling fearless and dumb like me, jump off the rocks into the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;auckland&quot;&gt;Auckland&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/ferry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ferry ride to Tiritiri Matangi wildlife sanctuary&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Ferry ride to Tiritiri Matangi wildlife sanctuary --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this not somewhere I ever travelled to since I lived here, because it was my home base for the semester I got to know it fairly well and can give my feedback. To be quite honest, apart from starting or ending your travels, I wouldn’t spend too much time here. There are definitely things to do (i.e. go up the Sky Tower, take a ferry to the nearby islands, visit museums) but they aren’t as unique as the other excursions you could experience in different parts of the country. New Zealand is all about nature, not its cities. My recommendation would be to stay a night or two just to gather your bearings when you first fly in, for example, and then start heading out to the rest of the country.
(Note: Auckland is where I started my Kiwi Experience trip so all the following locations are in the order that I visited them on this one trip)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;coromandel&quot;&gt;Coromandel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/hotwater.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Digging holes on Hot Water Beach at sunrise&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Digging holes on Hot Water Beach at sunrise --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coromandel Peninsula is a beautiful area that many Kiwis take advantage of for beach holidays. It is home to Hot Water Beach, a natural phenomenon unlike anything I had never experienced before. Essentially, you bring a shovel out to the beach, dig yourself a little hole, and then bam! - you got yourself a hot tub. The geothermal activity underneath the beach heats up the water (be careful! it can be very hot). The Coromandel is also home to Cathedral Cove, most well-known for its appearance in the Chronicles of Narnia. When I visited, the beach was closed from a recent storm, so I kayaked by it and still got to see it from the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;waitomo&quot;&gt;Waitomo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waitomo is a stop really only for one thing: glow worm caves. I had visited some free glow worm caves earlier in the semester so I didn’t pay for the cave excursion but, when I go back to New Zealand, this will definitely be something I want to do. One man I was traveling with had been all over the world and claimed that the cave excursion was one of the best things he’s ever done. The glow worms are truly a unique sight, giving the illusion of a night sky from inside the caves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rotorua&quot;&gt;Rotorua&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/zorb.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Zorbing!!!&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Zorbing!!! --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rotorua is a town you could spend a couple days in. It’s not the cleanest but it offers a lot of unique tourist activities. It is most well-known for its geothermal activity, so there lots of geysers that you can visit (beware: it smells like rotten eggs). I fulfilled my childhood dream of Zorbing, which is basically rolling down a hill in a giant hamster ball. There are also Mario Kart-like karts you can ride here (I did them in Queenstown- a ton of fun!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/tamaki.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Performance at Tamaki Village&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Performance at Tamaki Village --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Rotorua offers the quintessential tourist activity of experiencing the native culture. New Zealand was inhabited by the native Maori before England came over. They have done a MUCH better job of preserving their native culture than the US has. The Tamaki Village is run by a Maori family. They give you a great overview of Maori culture, from fighting to dancing to playing, and end the night with a wonderful hangi feast, which is where they cook the food underground. If you only have one chance to immerse yourself in the Maori culture while traveling in New Zealand, let this be the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mt-maunganui&quot;&gt;Mt. Maunganui&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/mount.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the top of the Mount&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- View from the top of the Mount --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mt. Maunganui is not a typical place tourists would visit– I would argue its more of a vacation spot for the Kiwis. I traveled over here to meet a friend from school who lived in the area. It is a very beautiful, beach-y area with a must-do hike up the Mount, but probably out of the way for someone road-tripping through the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taupo&quot;&gt;Taupo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/tongariro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Emerald Lake on the Tongariro Crossing&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Emerald Lake on the Tongariro Crossing --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/doom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mt. Doom also on the Crossing&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Mt. Doom also on the Crossing --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taupo is probably my favorite city on the North Island. It sits next to a beautiful lake and has the right balance of local and tourist vibes. Taupo is also  home to the World’s Best McDonald’s!! There are excursions you can take out on the lake (I went on a sailboat) and also excursions that are a bit more adventurous, such as the Tongariro Crossing or skydiving. I didn’t get the chance to go skydiving but I did do the Crossing and would definitely recommend it (if you are in decent shape). There are other places you can stay if you want to do the Crossing; Taupo is just one common option. We had a bus take us over early in the morning and spent practically all day hiking one of the best walks in New Zealand. It is challenging (they didn’t name one set of stairs the Devil’s Staircase for nothing) but it is full of amazing views. Make sure you bring plenty of water and snacks and layers, as you would any hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/huka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!--  --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huka Falls is also an incredible sight and located just outside of Taupo. It is easily the fastest and most powerful water stream I have ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;river-valley&quot;&gt;River Valley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;River Valley was basically a stopover in the middle of nowhere on our Kiwi Experience trip between Taupo and Wellington since they are quite far apart. The hostel we stayed at offered river rafting, which many other people in the group took advantage of. There can be long stretches of driving on a road-trip, so I would recommend making stopovers like this if need be. The great thing about New Zealand is that you’ll most likely always find something to do wherever you stay, even in a place as remote as this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wellington&quot;&gt;Wellington&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images//north/cablecar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Cable car ride overlooking Wellington&quot; class=&quot;image-fluid col-md-8&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;!-- Cable car ride overlooking Wellington --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wellington is the capital of New Zealand and mostly known as a student-friendly city. As I mentioned with Auckland, New Zealand isn’t known for their cities but Wellington is a place you can definitely spend a night or two in. There are museums, great restaurants, a cable car, etc. This is also where you can take a ferry to the South Island if you are continuing your trip. For me, Wellington was as far south as I went on my trip– I headed back up north after this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-takeaways&quot;&gt;The Takeaways…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone traveling throughout the North Island, here are the main things I would keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;takeaway&quot;&gt;Plan out your route well. Unlike the South Island, where you can cut across the island at some points or make a nice giant loop, on the North Island, things are very spread out vertically. If you have the time, go up north from Auckland but recognize that it will be “out of the way” if you are ultimately heading South.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;takeaway&quot;&gt;Spend a little money: While you may definitely spend money on big excursions on the South Island (especially in Queenstown), I found that the North Island might require a little bit more flexibility in budget. Things like sailing in the Bay of Islands and Taupo, glow worm caves, the Tongariro Crossing (need to pay for the bus pickup and drop-off if you don’t drive), and Hobbiton (which I didn’t visit but my dad and brother did and LOVED it) are all things that are completely worth the experience but do require some funds. There aren’t as many free things to see and do in the North as compared to the South.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;takeaway&quot;&gt;Paper maps/guidebooks: this is a tip I also included for the South Island but it still applies. I’m used to using Google for everything: maps, accommodation searching, drive times, etc. However, on this trip, we faced limited data, limited cell service, and limited battery life, all of which made paper guides our biggest source of help. A friend gave me the Lonely Planet New Zealand Guidebook for my birthday last year and it was essential to finding hostels and other information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">During my semester abroad at Auckland University, I had a 2 week mid-semester break, which I used to travel around the North Island of New Zealand using the Kiwi Experience bus route. Essentially, this is a pre-determined tour with various stops throughout all of New Zealand. Through this company, you can book excursions and hostels, making it very convenient for a solo backpacker like me to travel around without renting a car, worrying about being alone, etc. This post won’t go too much into the details of my time with Kiwi Experience but will instead focus on what I saw on the North Island throughout my entire semester, including other weekend trips. To make things organized, I’ll start with my weekend trips (since they were all north of the Kiwi Experience trip) and then work my way down south. At the end I have included a tips section with a summary of advice I would give to anyone about to travel through the North Island.</summary></entry></feed>